Trista Townsend

Junior developer and animator

Summary

Web development and robotics instructor with a background in character animation. Experienced in the languages of JavaScript, Ruby, Rails, Node.js, Go and SQL, to name a few. I love to finding creative solutions with code and technology, and combining those skills with interactivity to make a difference in day to day tech and user interactions.

https://github.com/t-townsend

Experience

Instructor at Langara College

June 2018 - Present

Instructor of Intro to Coding Using Robotics, in the continuing studies department. I develop curriculum, present Javascript coding and robotic design concepts, culminating to battlebots, using EV3 mindstorm robot kits.

Teaching Assistant at Langara College

April 2018 - Present

Provided teaching and support for various classes in the Web Development program at Langara College. I have done tutoring, presenting material, working one on one with groups, problem solving and debugging code, and marking tests and assignments.

Lead Animator

November 2017 - Present

Instructor at Langara College

July 2018 - July 2018 (1 month)

Taught and facilitated a Robotics summer camp for two weeks, for children. I developed curriculum, presentations, and presented the material to the class. The course covered writing code in C, and developing autonomous programming, using VEX iq robots. I integrated engineering concepts and robotic design, as well as how to program robots effectively, from joystick programs to line following.

Teaching Assistant at Langara College

January 2018 - June 2018 (6 months)

Provided teaching and support for the continuing studies class Intro to Coding with Robotics.

Freelance Designer

October 2016 - January 2018 (1 year 4 months)

Created illustrations and designs for private clients in Photoshop, Illustrator and Flash. Projects include a children's book, branding of a client's podcast page and icons for a website.

Animator at Atomic Cartoons

August 2017 - October 2017 (3 months)

Flash animator on the Marvel Super Heroes Adventures web content, featuring Spiderman.

Flash Generalist at Global Mechanic

June 2016 - September 2016 (4 months)

Working in Flash in the areas of Animation, Design, Scene Setup and Builds.

Flash Animator at Global Mechanic

May 2016 - May 2016 (1 month)

Animated using Adobe Flash, as per storyboard and dialogue track.

Posing and Layout Artist at DHX Media

April 2016 - May 2016 (2 months)

Pose characters in a scene as per storyboard, for the production of Chuck's Choice.

Posing and Layout Artist at DHX Media

September 2015 - December 2015 (4 months)

Posing and scene layout for My Little Pony, Season 6.

Posing and Layout Artist at DHX Media

July 2015 - September 2015 (3 months)

Accomplished posing and scene layout for the production of Transformers Rescue Bots, Season 3.

Posing and Layout Artist at DHX Media

September 2014 - July 2015 (11 months)

Accomplished posing and scene layout for the production of My Little Pony, Season 5.

Posing and Layout Artist at DHX Media

February 2015 - April 2015 (3 months)

Accomplished posing and scene layout for the DVD release of Equestria Girls: Friendship Games.

Posing and Layout Artist at DHX Media

August 2014 - September 2014 (2 months)

Accomplished posing and scene layout for the production of Looped.

Animation Revisionist at DHX Media

July 2014 - August 2014 (2 months)

Revised scenes as per director and client's notes.

Posing and Layout Artist at DHX Media

December 2013 - June 2014 (7 months)

Accomplished posing and scene layout for the production of Littlest Pet Shop, season 3.

Digital Storyboard Painter at Bardel Entertainment

August 2013 - September 2013 (2 months)

This was a short contract, in order to get a pitch ready. I coloured backgrounds, characters and props. In some cases, I was also asked to design the background, and do the line work that was needed.

Director, Designer, Animator, Sound Designer, Colourist, Editor at Freelance Animation & Design June 2013 - August 2013 (3 months)

I designed and animated two commercials for Counting Sheep Coffee Company. I did all roles on my own, from design to finished editing.

Background Artist at Big Bad Boo Studios

May 2011 - July 2011 (3 months)

Worked with the storyboard to create backgrounds for scenes, and cleaned up the drawings using Photoshop.

Intern at Anifex

October 2009 - November 2009 (2 months)

Intern at Cirkus

May 2009 - July 2009 (3 months)

Puppet Builder and Costume Assistant

October 2007 - December 2007 (3 months)

Laica Editor at Atomic Cartoons

February 2007 - October 2007 (9 months)

Education

CodeCore Developer Bootcamp

Certificate, Full stack development, 2017 - 2017

Capilano University

Commerical Animation, Animation, Interactive Technology, Video Graphics and Special

Effects. 2011 - 2013

Emily Carr Institute of Art & Design

BMA, Film, Animation, Video, Sound Design, 2003 - 2006

Trista Townsend

Junior developer and animator



Contact Trista on LinkedIn